

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211











Product Owner with 3 years of experience in product strategy, business analysis, product definition, user experience, interaction and product design in both Domestic and International Circuits. Highly capable Techno-functional Business Analyst.

Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MS/MSc(Science) [Management and

Notice Period: 2 Months

Finance]

Current Designation: Assistant Manager

Current Company: Ernst & Young

Current Location: Chennai

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Mumbai Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Business Analyst

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Consultant, Business Analyst, Business Analysis, Business Process Transformation, Project Management, Risk Management, Product Management, Requirement Gathering, Market Research, Competitor

Analysis, Scrum Master, Six Sigma, Waterfall, Presales, Agile, JIRA, SQL

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Product Owner with 3 years of experience in product strategy, business analysis, product definition, user experience, interaction and product design in both Domestic and International Circuits. Highly capable Techno-functional Business Analyst with over 8 years of experience in Software Product Development & Implementation.

Work Experience

- Ernst & Young as Assistant Manager Aug 2020 to Till Date
- Newgen Software Technologies as Lead Business Analyst Sep 2012 to Aug 2020
- Newgen Software Technologies Limited as Consultant (Product Owner)

Sep 2012 to Mar 2020

Consultant (Product Owner)

July 2017 - March 2020

Manager - Products & Solutions [Lead Business Analyst]

July 2016 - June 2017

Associate Manager - Products & Solutions [Sr. Business Analyst]

January 2015 - June 2016

Senior Executive - Products & Solutions [Business Analyst]

September 2012 - December 2014

Roles/Responsibilities - Product Owner

- * Managed Product Strategy and support charting the Product Vision for creating an application tightly integrated with multiple Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) Engines.
- * Assisted strategically to collect, aggregate and analyse product requirements from all stakeholders (customers, Project Sponsors and other senior stakeholders). Worked closely with the stakeholders to align the vision and
- * Co-ordinated with 8 Scrum Teams (incl. Third Party Teams) to help deliver an API-centric product. Acted as a Subject Matter Expert in the respective domains (Finance and Procurement Modules).
- * Performed Competitor analysis with the assistance of the Pre-Sales and the CoE Teams to help identify areas of improvement and prioritize key functionalities.
- * Implemented a RACI model of Communication to ensure all stakeholders were informed about product improvements and next steps at regular and pre-defined intervals.
- * Modelled processes using various notations (Use Cases, Activity Diagrams, Business Process Modeling Notation, Workflows, Swim lanes) to help elucidate requirements using workflows.
- * Gathering functional, business process requirements, documenting the As-Is and To-Be Scenarios. Broke down requirements into Features, Epics and Backlog Items* Prioritized/ Re-Prioritized the backlog basis business objectives, focused on building and delivering maximum value within the constraints of time and resources

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

functionalities and resolve issues (if any).

Roles/Responsibilities - Business Analyst

- * Responsible for providing consultative solutions to clients across multiple geographies by recommending Industry standard and best practises.
- * Proficiency in F&A Banking Business process optimization, intelligent automation with IT-BPM-Digital synergy, focusing on process efficiency, IT enablement and digital solution themes.
- * Worked with Deloitte, KPMG and E&Y to help automate and optimize business processes using BPM and RPA Applications.
- * Review clients' Business Processes and recommend To-Be Processes by providing a value stream mapping and developing recommendations for improvement
- * Gathering functional, business process requirements, documenting the As-Is and To-Be Scenarios in the form of Requirement Documents [PDD/ SRS/ FSD] and User Stories.

Infosys Technologies Limited as Systems Engineer Jun 2008 to Aug 2010

Roles/Responsibilities

- * Worked on software development and maintenance for Citi Private Bank. Comprehensive knowledge and understanding of Citi client's personalized wealth management induction program 'Project OneSource'.
- * Configuration controlling the team's quality and handling the off-shore's releases by managing a team of three.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Anna University, Chennai in 2008

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (Management and Finance) from University of Bath, United Kingdom in 2011

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Scrum Product Owner Lean Six Sigma Green Belt

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
MS OFFICE PACKAGE		2020	9 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
Waterfall, Agile, JIRA		2020	5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
SQL		2020	9 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
Balsamiq		2020	9 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
PROCESS MAPPING		2020	9 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
Value Stream Mapping		2020	9 Year(s) 7 Month(s)
Requirement analysis		2020	7 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
Product Strategy		2020	4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
backlog prioritization		2020	4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
MS Visio, IBM Blueworks		2020	7 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Tamil				
Malayalam				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved @ 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.